<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>draft on David Thuman</title>
    <link>https://davidthuman.org/categories/draft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in draft on David Thuman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidthuman.org/categories/draft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Updating Congress</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/updating-congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/updating-congress/</guid>
      <description>The process of data transfer between humans is an education optimization and learning problem.
Words (auditory), pictures (visual), or both
How long do speeches need to be? Is there a drop off of concept retainment for longer speeches?
It is actually good that States have some political freedom and divergence from the federal government. They can act each as independent experiments of policies and laws. Imagine a three dimensional space. Let’s take a vector in this space to represent the type (form, style, shape) of government (policies, branches, administrative function) that the federal government follows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The First-Principles Design to Your Society</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-first-principles-design-to-your-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-first-principles-design-to-your-society/</guid>
      <description>Existentialism # General Framework
Religion or Philosophy or Nothing?
From physics to Existentialism
Why Existentialism
Sea of endless purposes, but you can pick one
With your picked purpose, a clear path can be made
To move around intellectually one must first pick a general framework to work within. A framework is needed to give your thoughts motivation and relativity compared with others.
Why Humans Collect # The objective biology of it</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Mathematical Representation</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/a-mathematical-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/a-mathematical-representation/</guid>
      <description>Why Math # A true understanding of any system (a system can really represent anything: the United States’ economy, the hydrogen atom in quantum mechanics, a sports game, etc.) must be scientific. When investigating anything, a question of &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; can be asked at any level of the system. If we keep asking why, we will inevitably reach the discipline of physics, where the language is mathematics. To understand is to quantify, and if things are too heuristic or qualitative, we must create a mapping or model to understand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Goal</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/my-goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/my-goal/</guid>
      <description>My goal in life is to increase human happiness.
This is a quite broad and general goal, something that everyone should be able to get behind.
However, I must admit that the objective reason for this being anyone’s goal is beyond me.
Objective right and wrong, good or bad, moral or immoral comes from ones basic personal beliefs. The only objective fact we have in life is that there is no objective; no true purpose, no true good, no true reason why we are here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excess Value in Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/excess-value-in-capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/excess-value-in-capitalism/</guid>
      <description>An objects should be based on its raw material inputs and time and energy to create. Capitalism inflates the price of certain things based on location, as it is a limited value, and the supple of that thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crime and Punishment</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/crime-and-punishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/crime-and-punishment/</guid>
      <description>In a society there will always be people that break the rules. We will leave the discussion of the nature of these rules for later, and focus on how to treat and process the ‘rule breakers’. Lets first start with the trivial solution.
The trivial solution would be that of zero, doing nothing. If the thought of doing nothing to a person who breaks a particular rule seems reasonable, then the rule itself is probably at fault for the illogical solution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Document, Voting, and Argument Database (DVAD)</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/document-voting-and-argument-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/document-voting-and-argument-database/</guid>
      <description>I have tried to start making this.
The concept of creating some type of application, whether that be a website, app, etc., first came through my mind around senior year of high school. The idea of the website ‘wethepeople.com’ at first was going to be site where clear, detailed information about politics, elections, Congress would be easily accessible to all. I wanted summaries of legislature that were going through Congress, outlines of candidates’ polices and ideas, as well as a history of all politician’s past action for an increased amount of accountability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Any System</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/engineering-any-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/engineering-any-system/</guid>
      <description>Is capitalism steady-state? Sending letters to the telegram to the iPhone Perfection is impossible to reach unless defined solely by mathematics, but even then measure certainty is still present. With this dynamic change, however, the product or system must still be stable and functioning Dynamic change must be allowed No system or product is perfect at conception Perfection can only be rigorously defined through mathematics, and even within math itself, it is impossible to reach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Existentialism</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/existentialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/existentialism/</guid>
      <description>General Framework # Religion or Philosophy or Nothing? # From Physics to Existentialism # Why Existentialism # Sea of endless purposes, but you can pick one # With your picked purpose, a clear path can be made To move around intellectually one must first pick a general framework to work within. Now although this grounding framework cannot be used as a proven fact in an argument, if we are to build ideas from a first-principles standpoint these general frameworks are your starting assumption of how that world works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/freedom/</guid>
      <description>On the surface, freedom sounds like an amazing feature to have in your society. Why should I have people telling me how I can live my life? But even with that question, I can already see a flaw. Laws are clearly needed in a society, but they limit my freedom. So maybe freedom is not as strong as we first thought.
The question for building any society to break down the needed and desired features.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern Senate</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/modern-senate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/modern-senate/</guid>
      <description>Splitting up the group: The total count of Senate members in the United States Congress is 100. These individuals will be split up into 25 total groups of 4: randomly selected, at least one registered Republican and Democrat, meetings are recorded. Schedule Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday (In DC) 8:30 am: General Preparation, meeting, emails 11:30 am: Lunch 11:00 am: Voting 1:00 pm: Group Bill Discussion 4:00 pm: Break 4:30 pm: Free Collaboration Time 6:00 pm: END Thursday, Friday 6:00 am: Travel to represented State 8:00 am: Town Hall -&amp;gt; Speeches 9:00 am: Town Hall -&amp;gt; Discussion and Votes 10:30 am: Repeat Town Hall process 1:00 pm: Lunch 2:00 pm: Meetings, Discussions, Management Document, Voting, and Argument Database (DVAD): [[Make IT]] ?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steady-state Society</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/steady-state-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/steady-state-society/</guid>
      <description>To think that Capitalism is the steady-state or even the best economic system that humans can think of is a slap in the face of the engineering mindset. But even with that, it is true to say that it is the strongest and most powerful system that is in place today (2021). We can add higher-order Socialist terms to help correct some of the downfalls of Capitalism, but switching to Socialism, as our economic system would not be beneficial.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech and Personal Connection</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/tech-and-personal-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/tech-and-personal-connection/</guid>
      <description>When humans were first starting to socialize and group together, peer to peer connectivity was high but low in numbers. Tribal communities of max 150-200 people had high peer-to-peer connectivity. People in the tribe knew each other very closely and personally. They had to. Without a large fictional group to be organized by, people had to actually learn and trust each other.
But as technology increases, the level of peer-to-peer connectivity decreases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Filibuster</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-filibuster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-filibuster/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you’re designing a scheduling scheme for the CPU in your computer. Or in another abstraction, you’re attempting to run multiple programs on your computer. (The computer architecture analogy works well when dealing with systems that need to be optimized because CPU schedulers and computers in general have been optimized both on a heuristic and mathematical level. They are great examples of engineers and theorists doing amazing work.) In both of these scenarios, we have an entity that needs to manage multiple tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/optimization/</guid>
      <description>If a word does not have a defined functionality or purpose attached/associated with it, that word has not been optimized.
A sharper-than-normal rock might be used as a cutting tool, no one has sharpened this rock with purpose. It is just an object found in nature. It’s sharpness only arises from the action of erosion or gravity dropping it. Likewise, this rock has not been created by a human, an organism with the ability to think abstractly about things and to create with purpose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real Game Value</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/real-game-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/real-game-value/</guid>
      <description>Injecting real world value into video games. Often people implicate monetary values to in-game items but they have no other value except happiness. I want to somehow link work in the video game into work like data processing or computation.
maybe could be a rendering thing, people play the game and render the new world and send this data back to the devs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Government funded Social Media</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/government-funded-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/government-funded-social-media/</guid>
      <description>Like a beefier Twitter, Plaza would bring public spaces online.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Government funded Universities</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/government-funded-universities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/government-funded-universities/</guid>
      <description>There are too many PhD student and not enough professor positions. This creates a poor ‘academic paper’ environment. These people, I assume, want to do research more than teach, but I need good teachers and they want to do research. I would have them teach at all level, even if they are researching high level topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymptote Framework</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/asymptote-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/asymptote-framework/</guid>
      <description>Nothing in life is 100%, 1, or perfectly full. This can be proven in a quantum mechanical standpoint or through the semantics of classification. The idea of approaching the asymptote fills this gap and allows us to proceed normally with our life.
Some people would say that there is no such thing as a Utopia, these people would be right. So is there no point of attempting to get there if the end goal is impossible to achieve?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bill Text Length vs. Time to Vote</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/bill-text-length-vs-time-to-vote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/bill-text-length-vs-time-to-vote/</guid>
      <description>Tags: Research</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow Your Dreams</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/follow-your-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/follow-your-dreams/</guid>
      <description>Choose the path that you want to take. Fuck your formal education, what others tell you to do, or what your parents want you to do. This is your own life that you are living right now, and you only have one of it; so do what you want.
Strong words that often fail to float in the reality. The truth of the world, at the moment, is that optimizing for happiness or passion does not always lead to your best life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Process of Voting</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-process-of-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-process-of-voting/</guid>
      <description>With post-processing vote (less voter registration and more processing once votes are in), the official have more power to decide whether a vote is valid or not, giving a bigger threat than if it is harder for people to register in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Government</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-science-of-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-science-of-government/</guid>
      <description>Or as John Adams says, the &amp;ldquo;Divine Science of Politicks.&amp;rdquo;
Before anything, I want to first lay down some common definitions so we get a similar sense of what we are dealing with here. To communicate effectively, we must have a strong basis to build upon.
government (noun): the body of persons that contribute the governing authority of a political unit or organization
governing (verb): to exercise continuous sovereign authority over</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Be an Engineer?</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/why-be-an-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/why-be-an-engineer/</guid>
      <description>Often when I meet new people, both my major(s) and my future employment come up. I am always honest with them; I am an engineering physics and computer science double major, and I want to go into politics. This will often leave them in confusion, either asking how I want to connect my engineering degrees to politics or asking why I am majoring in two engineering disciplines.
When people ask the former, they try and connect my engineering knowledge to specific technical policy decision: whether to invest in this type of energy source, technical choices of internet restrictions and rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Humans Collect</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/why-humans-collect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/why-humans-collect/</guid>
      <description>The objective biology of it
We want to live to reproduce
But why would anyone want to live in pain?
What does better mean?
We collect to make everyone’s lives better
If you have ever received coaching or tips when generating a start-up, one common action is creating a mission statement. On the surface, mission statements seem to be an advertisement or public relation trick to boost the reputation of your company, and it some cases this maybe true.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
