<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>axiom on David Thuman</title>
    <link>https://davidthuman.org/tags/axiom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in axiom on David Thuman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidthuman.org/tags/axiom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The First-Principles Design to Your Society</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-first-principles-design-to-your-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-first-principles-design-to-your-society/</guid>
      <description>Existentialism # General Framework
Religion or Philosophy or Nothing?
From physics to Existentialism
Why Existentialism
Sea of endless purposes, but you can pick one
With your picked purpose, a clear path can be made
To move around intellectually one must first pick a general framework to work within. A framework is needed to give your thoughts motivation and relativity compared with others.
Why Humans Collect # The objective biology of it</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Mathematical Representation</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/a-mathematical-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/a-mathematical-representation/</guid>
      <description>Why Math # A true understanding of any system (a system can really represent anything: the United States’ economy, the hydrogen atom in quantum mechanics, a sports game, etc.) must be scientific. When investigating anything, a question of &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; can be asked at any level of the system. If we keep asking why, we will inevitably reach the discipline of physics, where the language is mathematics. To understand is to quantify, and if things are too heuristic or qualitative, we must create a mapping or model to understand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excess Value in Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/excess-value-in-capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/excess-value-in-capitalism/</guid>
      <description>An objects should be based on its raw material inputs and time and energy to create. Capitalism inflates the price of certain things based on location, as it is a limited value, and the supple of that thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crime and Punishment</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/crime-and-punishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/crime-and-punishment/</guid>
      <description>In a society there will always be people that break the rules. We will leave the discussion of the nature of these rules for later, and focus on how to treat and process the ‘rule breakers’. Lets first start with the trivial solution.
The trivial solution would be that of zero, doing nothing. If the thought of doing nothing to a person who breaks a particular rule seems reasonable, then the rule itself is probably at fault for the illogical solution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Any System</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/engineering-any-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/engineering-any-system/</guid>
      <description>Is capitalism steady-state? Sending letters to the telegram to the iPhone Perfection is impossible to reach unless defined solely by mathematics, but even then measure certainty is still present. With this dynamic change, however, the product or system must still be stable and functioning Dynamic change must be allowed No system or product is perfect at conception Perfection can only be rigorously defined through mathematics, and even within math itself, it is impossible to reach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/freedom/</guid>
      <description>On the surface, freedom sounds like an amazing feature to have in your society. Why should I have people telling me how I can live my life? But even with that question, I can already see a flaw. Laws are clearly needed in a society, but they limit my freedom. So maybe freedom is not as strong as we first thought.
The question for building any society to break down the needed and desired features.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steady-state Society</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/steady-state-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/steady-state-society/</guid>
      <description>To think that Capitalism is the steady-state or even the best economic system that humans can think of is a slap in the face of the engineering mindset. But even with that, it is true to say that it is the strongest and most powerful system that is in place today (2021). We can add higher-order Socialist terms to help correct some of the downfalls of Capitalism, but switching to Socialism, as our economic system would not be beneficial.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech and Personal Connection</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/tech-and-personal-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/tech-and-personal-connection/</guid>
      <description>When humans were first starting to socialize and group together, peer to peer connectivity was high but low in numbers. Tribal communities of max 150-200 people had high peer-to-peer connectivity. People in the tribe knew each other very closely and personally. They had to. Without a large fictional group to be organized by, people had to actually learn and trust each other.
But as technology increases, the level of peer-to-peer connectivity decreases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Filibuster</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-filibuster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/the-filibuster/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you’re designing a scheduling scheme for the CPU in your computer. Or in another abstraction, you’re attempting to run multiple programs on your computer. (The computer architecture analogy works well when dealing with systems that need to be optimized because CPU schedulers and computers in general have been optimized both on a heuristic and mathematical level. They are great examples of engineers and theorists doing amazing work.) In both of these scenarios, we have an entity that needs to manage multiple tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/optimization/</guid>
      <description>If a word does not have a defined functionality or purpose attached/associated with it, that word has not been optimized.
A sharper-than-normal rock might be used as a cutting tool, no one has sharpened this rock with purpose. It is just an object found in nature. It’s sharpness only arises from the action of erosion or gravity dropping it. Likewise, this rock has not been created by a human, an organism with the ability to think abstractly about things and to create with purpose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perspective</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/perspective/</guid>
      <description>Perspective (noun): the capacity to view things in their true relations or relative importance
The human body interfaces with the outside through our five senses: touch, sight, hearing, smell, and taste. This information from the outside world then filters through the body into the brain where it is processed. With regards to how someone sees the world, their perspective, variation can come in three different ways.
The first, and less complex one, is variation in our actual mechanics of gathering information from the outside world; these are the five senses stated before.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymptote Framework</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/asymptote-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/asymptote-framework/</guid>
      <description>Nothing in life is 100%, 1, or perfectly full. This can be proven in a quantum mechanical standpoint or through the semantics of classification. The idea of approaching the asymptote fills this gap and allows us to proceed normally with our life.
Some people would say that there is no such thing as a Utopia, these people would be right. So is there no point of attempting to get there if the end goal is impossible to achieve?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empathy</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/empathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/empathy/</guid>
      <description>One of the major building blocks of society is empathy.
To create a society that will help each other on multiple levels, empathy is needed to connect each member of the community.
Empathy alone cannot get your society to the full connection that is needed, there must also be an aspect of trust.
As the topic of page was first about empathy, which seems to be very important to people, I have developed a transition to maybe the more important sympathy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Be an Engineer?</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/why-be-an-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/why-be-an-engineer/</guid>
      <description>Often when I meet new people, both my major(s) and my future employment come up. I am always honest with them; I am an engineering physics and computer science double major, and I want to go into politics. This will often leave them in confusion, either asking how I want to connect my engineering degrees to politics or asking why I am majoring in two engineering disciplines.
When people ask the former, they try and connect my engineering knowledge to specific technical policy decision: whether to invest in this type of energy source, technical choices of internet restrictions and rules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Humans Collect</title>
      <link>https://davidthuman.org/posts/why-humans-collect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidthuman.org/posts/why-humans-collect/</guid>
      <description>The objective biology of it
We want to live to reproduce
But why would anyone want to live in pain?
What does better mean?
We collect to make everyone’s lives better
If you have ever received coaching or tips when generating a start-up, one common action is creating a mission statement. On the surface, mission statements seem to be an advertisement or public relation trick to boost the reputation of your company, and it some cases this maybe true.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
